Kyler Bomhof

Software Developer

616.405.0409 kdbomhof@gmail.com github.com/senyc Grand Rapids, MI

EXPERIENCE

kylerbomhof.com

07/2023 - Present

Mobile-centric website focusing on my skills, experience, and projects. Built with Next.JS, styled with tailwindcss, and deployed with Vercel.

typetest-cli

06/2023 - Present

A lightweight type speed tester for the terminal written in Python. Installable to any machine with the Python interpreter (and pip).

Software Developer Intern

Auto-Owners Insurance

05/2023 - Present

As a software developer I primarily built full stack applications. I followed agile methodologies on a team of business analysts, quality assurance engineers and other software developers.

I was personally responsible for front-end architectural decisions as well as their implementation. I largely used React.js, Typescript, Node, and SQL server.

Information Technology Intern

Haworth

05/2022 - 05/2023

I worked with the information security team to deploy security software to 7,500+ machines.

Wrote and deployed scripts using Microsoft Endpoint, Azure AD, and Configuration Manager.

Designed and built an app for employees to switch their wallpapers using the Azure Power Platform.

EDUCATION

Computer Science

Michigan Technological University 2023

Bachelor of Science - B.Sc

- GPA of 3.62
- Member of University Innovation Fellows
- · IT Oxygen team lead working with machine learning

SUMMARY

Software developer passionate about the systems he writes, and software he architects. Personal advocate for keeping code testable, and actually tested.

Kyler has Professional experience with full-stack development, working with teams, and utilizing the scrum framework.

SKILLS

Typescript/JS Advanced Python Expert Advanced React.js Node.js Advanced Advanced Linux Bash Advanced Git Expert SOL Intermediate CSS/SCSS Intermediate Intermediate Lua С Advanced C++Intermediate Vim Expert

Ruby Intermediate
Object Oriented Programming Intermediate

Time Management
Agile Methodologies
Team Management

Testing